# Mike Rubart

 Salt Lake City, UT
 ■ mrubart@gmail.com
 ■ 801-739-5241
 in linkedin.com/in/mikerubart

## **SUMMARY**

Experienced Senior Level Software Engineer with expertise in ASP.NET, C#, and DevOps. Developed and maintained web applications for prior authorizations, appeals submission, and fraud reporting, automated X12 and FHIR API validation, and optimized Oracle and T-SQL databases. Led junior developers in coding standards, debugging, and database optimization, and participated in hiring processes for various development roles.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Software Engineer III**

**University of Utah Health Plans** 

April 2020 - Current, SLC, UT

- Created and maintained internal and external facing web applications to help facilitate users obtain prior authorizations, submit appeals, organize sanction information, and Fraud Waste and Abuse reporting.
- Executed DevOps responsibilities including enhancing server performance, managing certificates, and deploying code efficiently.
- Automated process to validate X12 documents, i.e. 834 and 837 files as well as validate and maintain FHIR API, utilizing R4 and R5 standards.
- Created and optimized many database scripts for Oracle and T-SQL databases.
- Guided junior developers on implementing coding standards, debugging techniques, and database optimization.
- Conducted interviews for senior and junior developer roles.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

ArbiterSports.Com

November 2017 - March 2020, Sandy, UT

- Played a major role in the planning, research, and selection of new technology for future applications and enhancements including Unit Testing templates using xUnit, .NET Core, and React.
- Mentored junior developers on best practices, coding standards, debugging, and database optimization.
- Integrated Avatax sales tax platform on website and NetSuite accounting software.
- Defined business requirements and technical specifications with product managers.
- Acquired proficiency in various reporting processes including Windward, ActiveReports, and OfficeOpenXML to develop, optimize, and enhance the visual appeal and efficiency of reports.
- Interviewed candidates for senior and junior developer positions.

#### Software Analyst/Developer

Staywell LLC

July 2014 - October 2017, Salt Lake City, UT

- Maintained, enhanced and stabilized previously outsourced web application.
- Improved metric reporting process by leveraging stored procedure and code optimization from several hours to 15 seconds.
- Utilized Visual Studio for development projects involving ASP.NET C# MVC, JavaScript, JQuery, Knockout, CSS, and requireJS.
- Used MongoDb, Oracle 11g and MS SQL databases.
- Trained on AngularJS and NodeJS for possible migration.

## Senior Software Engineer II

Monavie Inc

February 2011 - July 2014, South Jordan, UT

- Instrumental in the maintenance and enhancement of internal and client facing websites.
- Engaged with project managers, business analysts, and technical analysts to align with business requirements and technical specifications, ensuring punctual project delivery.
- $\bullet \ \ Wrote \ technical \ specifications \ for \ developers \ from \ business \ requirements, including \ time \ estimations.$
- Conducted peer code reviews and unit testing to ensure high quality code.

## **Lead Developer**

## **Xennsoft Corp**

- Led team of over 20 developers supporting multiple external clients.
- Administered all code base management using tortoise SVN during simultaneous short and long development cycles.
- Facilitated the creation of code standards and enforcement process.
- Integral in the planning of application architecture and facilitated implementation.
- Scheduled and facilitated team meetings for training and project post mortems.

## **EDUCATION**

## M.S. - Cybersecurity and Information Assurance

Western Governors University • Sale Lake City, Utah • 2020

## **B.S. – Computer Information Systems**

Western Governors University • Salt Lake City, Utah • 2006

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

#### **Certified Ethical Hacker Certification**

Mar 2020

#### **SKILLS**

Technical Skills: C#, ASP.NET MVC, ASP.NET Core, Razor, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML5, React JS, AWS Amplify, Python, EDI X12

Databases: MS SQL, Oracle, MongoDB, Stored Procedures, Functions

Tools: Visual Studio 2022, TFS, Git, SVN, SQL Studio, VS Code, GitHub, TOAD Data Point, MS Office

Other: Agile, SCRUM, Project Management, Jira, Service Now